这下我们再也找不到他了
Now, we're never gonna find him.
突袭行动会有发现的
The raid will turn up something.
只要有任何线索  我们就能找到他
And when it does, we will find him.
打开
Open it.
谢谢你  宝贝
Thank you, baby.
谢谢你来救我出去
Thank you for getting me out of there.
玛雅  罗文在哪
Maya, where's Rowan?
你上次见他是什么时候
When is the last time you saw him?
他们给你看了吗  你父亲关我的地方
Did they show it to you -- the place where your father kept me?
你看到了吗
Did you see it?
如果你不合作
If you're not willing to cooperate,
不告诉我们你知道的一切
if you don't tell us everything you know --
你会怎么样  你什么都做不了
What are you gonna do to me? Not a damn thing.
我女儿来了  奥利维亚·波普就在这里
My daughter is here now. Olivia Pope is here. Now.
只要你们敢动我一根汗毛
You so much as lay a finger on me,
就等着收传票吧
and we will sue your ass.
告诉他们  丽芙
Tell 'em, Livvie.
让他们尝尝你的厉害
Handle them.
你们还没起诉她
You haven't charged her.
没错  正是如此
That's what I'm talking about.
这侵犯了我的权力
This is a violation of my rights.
我连自己被关在这的罪名都不知道是什么
They haven't even told me what I'm being accused of.
谋杀  恐怖行动  叛国  多着呢
Murder, terrorism, treason, to start.
起诉她  把她关起来
Charge her, and lock her up.
丽芙
Livvie.
至于我父亲
As for my father,
全力追捕  找到并杀了他
hunt him, find him, and kill him.
奥利维亚
Olivia.
Olivia!
丑      闻
第四季     第九集
■
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译：胖兔纯   磨旧的时光   冬麟   歌谣   暴龙蛋
我跟你说了多少次了
How many times do I have to tell you
翻译： 圈圈   小憨   章鱼X   roaddog
离我家远点
to stay away from my house?!
我知道哈维一定很伤心  我只想解释...
I know Javi must be upset, and I just wanted to explain --
哈维  你联系过他吗
Javi? Did you contact him?
校对：暴龙蛋      时间轴： 吉吉  贝贝  言  兜爹
你跟我儿子说过话了
Did you talk to my son?
我现在必须跟他谈谈
I need to talk to him now.
-哈维  -他不在
- Javi?! - No! He's not here.
后期：蜡笔小新的眉毛     总监：暴龙蛋   蓬蓬裙
-他在  -他去朋友家了
- He is. - He's at a friend's house.
他就在房间里  我追踪了他的手机信号
He's here in his room. I traced his phone.
宝贝  你还好吗  哈维  你还好吗
Oh, baby, are you okay? Javi, baby, are you okay?
你对他做了什么
What did you do to him?
你是不是又跟他说了什么你是间谍的谎言
Did you fill his head with your lies about being a spy?!
他是不是被你那通胡话吓坏了
Did you scare my son with that tired-ass crap?!
是不是
Did you?
Did you?!
如今我国境内的情况十分危急
The situation on the ground in my country is critical.
如果你们再不实行军事干预...
Every minute without military intervention --
美国一定会致力保护西安哥拉的民主
The U.S. is committed to preserving democracy in West Angola.
我向你保证  大使
You have my word, ambassador.
谢谢你  总统先生
Thank you, Mr. President.
谢谢前来  大使
Thank you, ambassador.
谢谢你  先生
Thank you, sir.
说吧  塞
Say it, Cy.
我不想等到事后再来劝你  先生
I don't want to second guess you, sir.
你知道我不愿发起战争
You know I don't want a war,
但他们公然在我国境内发动袭击
but they attacked us in our backyard.
他们必须血债血偿  这事必须有个了断
They have to pay. There need to be consequences.
我同意  我们必须反击
Agreed. We have to retaliate.
但两个月后
But two months down the line
当运输机载着第一批士兵遗体
when the first shipment of body bags
降落在多佛空军基地时
are unloaded from a C-130 at Dover --
为了什么
all for something
就为了那充其量勉强称得上的民主吗
that, at best, vaguely resembles democracy?
你有什么计划
What's your plan?
我还没想好
I don't have a plan yet.
想到了再来找我
Well, come back to me when you do.
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
奎恩·铂金斯
什么事
What?
你收到我信息了吗
Did you get my messages?
奎恩  什么事
Quinn, what?
库比亚克死了
Kubiak's dead.
他发现了哈克藏身在他的监视车里并袭击了他
He spotted Huck in his surveillance van and attacked him.
哈克杀了库比亚克
Huck killed Kubiak?
-那他...  -他没事
- Is he... - No, he's fine.
等等
Wait.
哈克监视的是伊丽莎白·诺斯
Huck was on Elizabeth North.
没错  丽芙  他们之间有来往
That's the thing, Liv. They were meeting each other.
库比亚克  伊丽莎白·诺斯
Kubiak, Elizabeth North,
还有一个你绝对想不到的人  副总统
and -- get this -- the vice president.
美国副总统  你确定吗
Of the United States? Are you sure?
我亲眼所见
I saw it with my own eyes.
而且诺斯和副总统有一腿  丽芙
And North and the vice president are screwing, Liv.
这也是我亲眼所见  简直不堪
Saw that with my own eyes, too. It's gross.
你还在监视伊丽莎白·诺斯吗
Are you still on Elizabeth North?
我跟丢了
I lost her.
我得先照顾哈克
I kind of had to take care of Huck.
需要我继续监视她吗
Do you want me to get back on her?
不用了  当我没说
You know what? Never mind.
伊丽莎白
Elizabeth.
有什么能帮到你的吗
How can I help you?
你不能  或者该说  是不愿意
You can't...or won't.
-你说什么  -我的手机
- Excuse me? - My phone.
我出高价让你排查的那部
The one I overpaid you to debug.
你说是被我女儿的电脑感染了的那部
The one you claimed was infected by my daughter's computer.
但另有人跟我说
I got a second opinion.
是塞勒斯·比尼黑了我的手机
Turns out it was bugged by Cyrus Beene,
所以你要么知道这件事
so you either knew that
要么你就是失职了
or you're just straight-up bad at your job.
我以为我们互相理解
I thought you and I understood each other,
互相尊重呢
had a mutual respect going on.
地狱里有个特别的地方
There's a special place in hell
那是为不支持其他女同胞的恶女准备的
for women who don't support other women.
地狱里也有个差不多的地方
There's a special place in hell
是为那些只会用大道理
for women who spout that tired quote
为自己辩解的女人准备的
to justify their bad behavior.
你的生活真是精彩啊  莉兹
You lead a very exciting life, Liz,
又是杀人犯  又是男妓的
consorting with a wide range of murderers, prostitutes,
甚至还有副总统
even a vice president.
我的生活不及你的好朋友塞勒斯一半精彩
My life's not half as exciting as your pal Cyrus'.
我们现在还没开战
We're not at war yet.
总统仍然在考虑其它选择
The president is still considering his options.
因为还有其它的还击方法  不用...
Because there are other ways to retaliate without --
我等会再打给你  议员
I'll call you back, senator.
伊丽莎白·诺斯刚刚来找我了
Elizabeth North just paid me a visit.
要出事了  我们得做好准备
Something's coming. We need to prepare.
《时代周刊》刚刚联系了我
I just got a question from the Times
询问有关你照片的事情
about photos of you.
你的艳照
Sexy-time photos of you.
照片上的男人叫迈克尔
The man in the photos, his name is Michael --
他为伊丽莎白·诺斯工作
is working for Elizabeth North.
还是我们自己党派的  真好
Our own party. Of course.
还有别的  伊丽莎白和你的副总统有一腿
There's more. Elizabeth is in bed with your vice president,
不管是哪种意义上都有一腿
both literally and figuratively.
新闻已经发布了
News hit the wires.
-连照片一起吗  -目前只是快报
- Photos, too? - Just a bulletin.
等等
Hold it.
照片流出来了
Photos are out.
天哪
Oh, sir. Oh, sir.
我现在我们只能用同性间的性关系来形容
Explicit gay sex is how we're describing these photos,
这些刚刚泄露给BNC的照片
leaked to BNC just minutes ago.
白宫幕僚长
我们还在指望有证据能证明
We're still looking to confirm reports
那个人的男妓身份
that the other man is indeed a prostitute.
比尼完蛋了
白宫方面尚未发表评论
The White House has yet to comment,
但对总统来说  这绝不是个好消息
but this is hardly good news for the president,
塞勒斯肮脏的把戏
因为他已经承受着
who is already facing pressure
对西安哥拉宣战的压力
to declare war against West Angola.
先生  再说一次  我非常抱歉
Sir, again, I am so sorry.
-我们要怎么办  -先拖着
- How are we handling this? - For now, we stall.
白宫律师办公室正在鉴定
White House Counsel's Office is reviewing the photos
这些照片的真实性和这件事的法律性质
to determine their authenticity and legal status.
但你能确认这就是塞勒斯·比尼的艳照
But you can confirm they're of Cyrus Beene.
现在还不行
Not at this time.
为什么  难道塞勒斯有个
Why? Does Cyrus have a
我们没见过的双胞胎兄弟
twin brother we don't know about?
不是吧  阿什莉
Really, Ashley? Really?
发生什么事了
What the hell is going on over there?
什么  西安哥拉  流感恐慌
With what? West Angola? Flu scare?
快去打你的流感针吧  大卫
Get your flu shot, David.
你知道我必须得调查这事
You know I'm gonna have to investigate this.
那就让他去调查  他能找到什么
So let him investigate. What will he find?
当我发现迈克尔为伊丽莎白·诺斯工作的时候
When I found out Michael worked for Elizabeth North,
我删掉了所有的邮件和短信
I deleted all my e-mails and texts,
现在看来好像不太明智
which, in retrospect, doesn't look great.
但这并不违法
But it's not illegal.
我们如果这么做的话
We're talking about months and months
要面对的可是长达几个月的国会听证会
of congressional hearings if we take this on.
传票  特别检察官
Subpoenas. Special prosecutors.
除非律师办公室给出他们的意见
Until the counsel's office gets a bearing
搞清楚这些照片的性质和来源
on what these photos are and where they came from,
不然我不会发表更多评论
I'll have no further comment.
在我们确定是否要为此抗争之前
We can't confirm or deny
我们不能确认或者否认任何事情
until we know if we're fighting this or not.
我们要抗争吗
Are we fighting this?
总统先生
Mr. President?
动手吧
We fight this.
我已经起草了一份初步协议
I've drawn up a preliminary contract.
你说什么
Excuse me?
初始期限是三年
A three-year initial term,
迈克尔在每年的婚姻生活中收到一百万美金
in which Michael receives $1 million per year of marriage.
-你说什么  -迈克尔得全额退款
- What? - Michael will be required to repay you in full
加上一百万的罚金
with a million-dollar penalty,
如果他违反了任何协议条款
if he violates any of the terms of the contract,
保密条款  公共形象  随机的药物检测
confidentiality, public appearances, random drug testing.
所以  塞勒斯算是买下我了
So, Cyrus would basically own me.
你指的是租用的反义词吗
You mean as opposed to just renting?
婚姻是解决这事的唯一办法
Marriage is the only way to sell this.
美国人民喜欢这样的爱情故事
America loves a love story.
美国人民会为爱原谅所有犯下的错
America will forgive anything for love.
不然的话  这事就是另一桩华盛顿性丑闻
Otherwise, it's just another D.C. sex scandal.
好吧  我同意
Fine. I'll, I’ll do it. I'm in.
很好  塞勒斯呢
Good. Cyrus?
等等
Wait. Wait. Wait.
等一下
Just a minute.
你同意
You're in?
我想知道你为什么会同意
Why is that, I wonder?
你现在是男妓史上最出名的人了
You are now the most famous gay hooker in gay-hooker history.
你可以写本书卖给好莱坞
You could write a book. Sell it to Hollywood.
在色情版里倾情出演
Play yourself in the porn version,
就叫"在塞勒斯·比尼体内"
"Inside Cyrus Beene."
你应该最了解我不过了
You know me better than that.
我一点都不了解你
I don't know you at all.
40年来我一直未公开承认同性恋身份
I was in the closet for 40 years.
40年来  我和女人发生性关系
I spent four decades having sex with women,
在女人的两腿之间
between the thighs of women,
就我自身而言  毫无快感  也不理解
which I, for one, never enjoyed or quite understood.
在此期间  我只和两个男人上过床
In that whole time, I only ever slept with two men.
其中一位是我此生挚爱
One of them was the love of my life.
另外一位是个男妓
The other was a prostitute,
对我来说  后者无可否认是个糟糕的决定
which was, admittedly, a terrible decision on my part.
但是这种方式...
But this... this...
这种方式既残忍又不公
this just seems cruel... and unfair.
很抱歉  丽芙
I'm sorry, Liv.
我做不到  我不能这样对詹姆斯
I can't... I won't do that to James.
我才不要和这个人结婚
I am not gonna marry this person.
这是昨晚所有的监控录像吗
This is all the footage from last night?
前门  后门  卫生间  凡是你想得到的
Front, back, restrooms. You name it.
-谢谢  -乐意效劳
- Thanks. - Pleasure.
罗文在搞内部清理
Rowan's cleaning house.
这是什么
What's that?
密杀令牌  这是B613的收尾流程
A kill card. It's the shutdown procedure for B613.
他们搞清理不能请搬家公司吗
They don't just hire some movers?
一直以来都有一个计划预案
There's always been a plan in place
以防B613的身份遭到泄露
in case B613's identity was compromised.
一小时前有个人想杀我
That card came off someone
这张牌就是从他身上掉出来的
who tried to kill me an hour ago.
几乎每一位曾效力于B613的特工
Just about everyone who worked at B613
现在都成了后患
is now considered a loose end.
用数字电台怎么样
Well, what about the numbers station?
我们可以提醒其他特工
We can warn the others.
我查过了  已经损坏了
I checked it. Already corrupted.
罗文用它联系那些毫无警惕的特工回总部
Rowan's using it to call unsuspecting agents home,
然后痛下杀手
then killing them.
哈克  查查这些车牌
Huck, run these plates.
交通摄像头  加油站摄像头
Traffic cams, gas-station security cams...
所有的摄像  找黑色林肯城市轿车
Everything. Black Lincoln town car.
等等  你要去找罗文吗
Wha-- wait. You're going after Rowan yourself?
他会来找我的  我打算先下手为强
He's coming after me. I plan to get to him first.
你自己小心
Watch your backs.
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?
外面
Out.
这么急找我何事  罗宾
Where's the fire, Robin?
罗文正对B613进行内部清理
Rowan's cleaning house on B613.
他锁定的目标是所有特工
He's got targets out on all the agents,
他弄了一副纸牌  牌上印着我们的照片
made up some kind of playing cards with our faces on them,
他要把我们逐一除掉
and he's taking us out one by one.
我觉得应该让你知道
I thought you should know.
你觉得这很好笑吗
Oh, that's funny to you?
明白了
Oh, snap.
你喜欢我
You like me.
我才不喜欢你
I don't like you.
你不想让我死
You don't want me dead.
我是想警告你
I wanted to warn you.
你喜欢我
You like me.
真贴心
It's sweet.
生命都充满意义了
It's life-affirming.
你给我下车
Get out of the car.
事实上  我们现在当场就可以
Doesn't the fact that we could both go any minute
让你明白...
make you want to just...
生命的意义  罗宾
affirm life, Robin?
不好意思  我迟到了
Sorry I'm... I'm late.
-我迟到了吗  -是的
- Am I late? - Yeah.
现在什么情况
Where are we?
我追踪了安德鲁  伊丽莎白
I tracked Andrew, Elizabeth,
库比亚克过去六个月的手机记录
and Kubiak's cellphones over the last six months.
直到昨晚之前  他们只有一次
And they've only ever been together in the same place
同时出现在同一个地点
one other time before last night.
那是什么时候
When was that?
凯特琳被谋杀当晚
The night Caitlin was murdered,
他们都在杰里米·温斯洛的律师事务所里
they were all at Jeremy Winslow's law firm.
我们得搞清楚
We need to find out
他们当晚为什么在那里  他们见面谈了什么
why they were there that night, what that meeting was about.
律所所有的开销都算在一位客户的账上
Everything at a law firm is billed to a client...
订书钉  铅笔  甚至空气
staples, pencils, air.
如果我们能确定是哪位客户  也许我们就能
If we can identify the client, maybe we can figure out
-知道他们的谈话内容  -很好
- what they were talking about. - Good.
我黑进了律师事务所的网络系统
I hacked into the law-firm network,
没有任何关于那晚会面的记录
and there was nothing about a meeting,
甚至没有他们去过律师事务所的记录
or them even being there that night.
我们得进去才行
We need to get inside.
我打赌肯定有什么书面形式的东西
I bet there's something on paper.
律师们钟爱纸质文件  就是这么怪
Lawyers still love paper. It's weird.
那家律所的门禁是高端生物识别多重模式
Access to the firm is advanced biometric, multiple modalities.
我们进不去  我们需要指纹才行
We can't get in. We'd need a fingerprint.
我们确实有根手指
Well, we do have a finger.
你有根手指
You have a finger?
凯特琳那晚去律师事务所
Caitlin went to the law firm that night
找她爸爸
looking for her dad.
她肯定撞见了伊丽莎白·诺斯和副总统
She must have seen the secret meeting
在秘密会面
wth Elizabeth North and the Vice President.
当她试图离开的时候
When she tried to leave,
她和丹·库比亚克为了那个文件夹发生争执
she fought with Dan Kubiak over that folder
里面是奥利维亚的照片
with pictures of Olivia.
我想我找到了
I think I found it.
好的  客户编号15226
Okay. Client code 15226.
能查到名字吗
Can you find a name?
15226  韦科
15226, Wacoinc.
韦科  德州城市还是石油公司
Waco. Like Texas? Oil, maybe?
杰克
Jake.
-拿着  -为什么
- Take it. - Why?
-你用得上  -我不需要枪
- You need it. - I don't need a gun.
我要枪有什么用
Why would I need a gun?
防身
For protection.
你父亲在清理后患
Your father is cleaning up.
这是密杀令牌
That's a kill card.
你知道的不比特工少
You know as much as any agent,
所以你对他来说也是个威胁
so you're a threat just the same.
我知道怎么开枪  只不过不用而已
I know how to shoot a gun, I just choose not to.
我的整个职业生涯中没用过枪
I've gone my whole career without needing one.
你的整个职业生涯中
You've gone your whole career
没和你父亲作对过
without going up against your father.
我爸爸不会杀我的
My father wouldn't kill me.
我肯定他想杀你
I'm sure he thinks the same about you.
好的  我来教你
All right. Refresher course.
格洛克26型  半自动手枪
Glock 26. Semiautomatic.
举起枪  准备射击
You hold it up. You're ready to fire.
心脏  臀部  头部
Heart, hips...head.
这样他们就任你宰割了
That's how you get a stop shot.
致命射击呢
What about a kill shot?
我们不用非得呆在这
We don't have to stay here, you know.
只要你开口  我就不找你父亲了
Say the word, I will stop trying to find your father.
我们可以收拾行李  远离这一切
We can pack up and leave all of this behind.
关上潘多拉魔盒
We can close Pandora's box...
重新回到太阳底下
And go back to the sun.
太阳很久之前就陨落了
The sun went down a long time ago,
而且再也不会升起来了
and it's not coming back up.
抱歉我来晚了  有事耽误了
Sorry I'm late. I got held up.
有丹·库比亚克的消息吗
Any word from Dan Kubiak?
还没找到那个白痴
That idiot's still M.I.A.
奥利维亚·波普咬着我不放
Olivia Pope is on my ass,
总统也没下令开战
and the president still hasn't declared war.
想聊一聊吗
Want to talk about it?
现在不想
Not at the moment.
塞勒斯·比尼的丑闻
The Cyrus Beene scandal
只会对白宫西厢不利
has only gotten worse for the West Wing,
总统已经推动
A presidency already struggling
第二任期内的议程来缓和事态了
with pushing their second-term agenda.
两个党派内的一些议员和议院领袖
Several senate and house leaders on both sides of the aisle
正强烈敦促塞勒斯·比尼辞职
are strongly urging Cyrus Beene to resign.
您看过尼克松的辞职信吗
You ever read Nixon's resignation letter?
"亲爱的国务卿先生
"Dear Mr. Secretary,
我谨辞去美国总统职务
"I hereby resign the office of President of the United States.
理查德·尼克松谨上"
Sincerely, richard nixon."
就这几句
That's it.
他做总统时最重要的文件
The most important document of his presidency.
就这么简单
Completely artless.
-我们这么办  -塞勒斯
- So here's how it's going to work. - Cyrus.
我提交辞职信
I'm going to hand you this letter,
您批准
and you're going to accept it.
您就说  "谢谢你一直以来的努力  塞勒斯
You'll say, "Thank you for your service, Cyrus.
我很荣幸"
It's been an honor."
我再回答
To which I will respond,
"总统先生  感到荣幸的是我"
"The honor, sir, was mine."
之后  我回到办公室
Once we've done that, I'll return to my office.
会有个人在那里等我
There will be a man there waiting for me.
他拿走我的徽章  送我上车
He'll take my badge and escort me to my car.
而您呢  先生  立即叫小红过来
You, sir, will immediately summon Red
讨论发表什么样的声明
and discuss what kind of statement to make.
她会建议您严厉谴责我
She'll want you to bury me.
您不同意  但她坚持
You'll say no, but she'll insist.
听她的
Listen to her.
打击我来为您自己树立威信
Build yourself up by knocking me down.
您就要开战了  一场恶战  愚蠢的战争
You have a war to fight -- a bad war, a stupid war.
如果是两天前
And if this were two days ago,
我会阻止您
I'd stop you from fighting it.
但到了这个时候
But this is today.
到了今天  先生  我  今天...
And today, sir, I'm -- today, s--
先生  我就是个笑话  最可笑的那个
Sir, I'm a joke. A punch line.
我没有发挥一点作用  总统先生
I am of no help to you, Mr. President.
而现在唯一能帮到您的
The only way to help you now...
就是离开
...is by leaving.
我不接受
I don't accept this.
"谢谢你一直以来的努力  塞  我很荣幸"
"Thank you for your service, Cy. It's been an honor."
-塞勒斯  -“谢谢你一直以来的努力  塞
- Cyrus. - "Thank you for your service, Cy.
我很荣幸"
It's been an honor."
"谢谢你一直以来的努力  塞
"Thank you for your service, Cy.
我很荣幸"  请说吧
It's been an honor." Please.
谢谢你一直以来的努力  塞
Thank you for your service, Cy.
我很荣幸
It's been an honor.
总统先生  感到荣幸的是我
The honor, sir... was mine.
为什么总统先生还没发表声明
Why hasn't the president issued a statement?
总统先生目前正在处理
The president is currently dealing
一起发生在美国本土的恐怖袭击
with a terrorist attack on American soil.
他正忙于确保该情况不会再次发生
He's a little busy ensuring that it never happens again.
下一个问题  马丁
Next question. Martin.
首席检察官传唤你是真的吗
Is it true you've been subpoenaed by the Attorney General?
目前就到此为止
That's all I have for you right now.
谢谢
Thank you.
我需要你回想一下3月25日的晚上
I'd like to direct your attention to the evening of March 25th.
当晚  比恩先生删除了他和那个被他召来的
That evening, Mr. Beene deleted all records of telephone calls
男妓之间的所有通话记录
and all e-mail correspondence with the prostitute
和电邮往来
whose services he had solicited.
-对此你知情吗  -不知情
- Were you aware of that fact? - No.
3月25日当晚
Did you assist Mr. Beene
你是否曾协助比恩先生
with the potential destruction of evidence
毁灭证据
on the evening of March 25th?
绝对没有
Absolutely not.
你有那晚的不在场证明吗
Do you have an alibi for that evening?
惠兰女士  我正在问你问题
Ms. Whelan, I asked you a question.
3月25日晚上你有不在场证明吗
Do you have an alibi for the night of March 25th?
请先停止记录
Let's go off the record.
我觉得我们还是不要问得太细了  大卫
I-I don't think we need to get into this, David.
文字记录的时候
I'm gonna be a little bit of a hardass here, okay,
我得严格一点
for the transcript.
你不用太慌
Don't get too rattled.
继续记录
Back on the record.
请记住你已宣誓保证所言属实
Please remember you are under oath.
我再问你一次
Let me ask you again --
3月25日当晚你有不在场证明吗
Do you have an alibi for the night of March 25th?
有
Yes.
谁
Who?
里奥·伯尔根
Leo Bergen.
3月25日晚上你和里奥·伯尔根在哪里
Where were you with Leo Bergen the night of March 25th?
-大卫  -惠兰小姐  现在正在记录呢
- David. - Ms. Whelan, we are on the record.
*...There's only you in my life*
在他家
At his house.
*The only thing that's right*
整晚都在吗
The whole night?
是的
Yes.
*My first love*
谢谢你  惠兰小姐
Thank you, Ms. Whelan.
-今天就这样  -大卫
- That will be all. - David.
就这样吧
That will be all.
*You're every breath that I take*
*You're every step I make*
你的电话  查理
Your phone, Charlie.
*And I*
帮我关机
Just turn it off.
*I want to share*
*All my love with you*
*No one else will do*
那是什么
What's that?
密杀令牌
A kill card.
这是B613的收尾流程
It's the shutdown procedure for B613.
*And your eyes*
*Your eyes, your eyes*
*They tell me how much you care*
*Oh, yes, you will always be*
糟了
Oh...Crap.
-你是来杀我的吗  -不是
- You came here to kill me? - No.
是
Yes.
*My endless love*
也许吧
Maybe?
去死吧你
Screw you.
我要是不杀了你  我就没命了
I had to kill you or someone would kill me.
我也是没有办法的  罗宾
It isn't exactly the greatest system, Robin.
你这个...
You lying...
满口扯谎的...
sack of...
人渣
crap!
不
No!
*Two hearts*
我一直没有动手
I was on the fence!
难道你也对此视而不见吗
Doesn't that mean anything to you?
*Two hearts that beat as one*
*Our lives have just begun*
最恶心的是
Worst part is,
你杀我之前还想上我
you wanted to screw me before you did it!
-我这有发现  -什么
- I got something. - What?
罗文的车牌在罗诺克城外
Rowan's license plate popped up
被交通监控捕捉到了
on a traffic cam outside Roanoke.
诺克斯维尔有一个B613的配电站
Well, there's a B613 switching station outside of Knoxville.
他可能是要去那
He could be headed there.
或者是要去曼斯菲尔德
Or he's going to Mansfield.
曼斯菲尔德  小城市
Mansfield. Small town.
远在外地  7级戒备的安全屋
Out of the area. Level 7 safe house.
你说得对  就是那了  多谢了  哈克
You're right. That's it. Thanks, Huck.
奥利维亚
Olivia.
-你来这干什么  -还记得这个吗
- What are you doing here? - Remember this?
你到底来干什么
What are you doing here?
《生命中最重要的歌》
"Songs in the key of life."
还记得我第一次放给你听的时候吗
Remember the first time I played this for you?
你来这里干什么
What are you doing here?
很多时候  我并不是个感情用事的人
I don't get sentimental about many things.
感情就是弱点
Sentimentality is a weakness.
但是尽管你的家人可以变着花样地
But despite the many ways that family
伤害你  操纵你  拒不承认
can hurt you and manipulate you and deny the very fact
他们的成功都是踩着你的肩膀
that their success is a product of yours,
但无论你多么努力
it is impossible to wipe away the pleasant memories
却还是无法抹去那些愉快回忆
no matter how hard one tries.
坐吧
Sit.
滚
Leave.
坐下
Sit.
虽然我说过不会再管你
I told you I was leaving you alone,
但那还不够
but that wasn't enough.
很显然只有我死了
Apparently you're only going to be happy
你才会高兴
when I'm dead.
你不会放手的
You're not leaving.
你从未放手过
You were never leaving.
你永远都不会不管我
You can never leave me alone
因为你无处可去
because you have no place to go.
你唯一有的
The only life you have
就是这段亲手塑造的可悲扭曲的人生
is the sad, twisted one you built here.
这段你隐藏在暗处
The one where you lurk in the shadows,
操纵牵线木偶
pull puppet strings,
假装没有你的保护
and pretend the world couldn't exist
世界将不复存在的人生
without your protection.
你无法改过自新
You can't disappear,
变成一个正常人  因为  爸爸
become a normal person, because, dad,
你不正常
you are not normal.
你是个病态的孤鬼
You're a sick, lonely man
只会撒谎  还称之为爱
who only knows how to lie and call it love.
你还有点良心吗
Could you be more ungrateful?!
你是我的骨肉
You're my flesh.
没有我  根本不会有什么奥利维亚·波普
There would be no Olivia Pope if not for me.
虽然很难承认
As difficult as it is to admit,
但我是个失败的父亲
I have failed as a father.
我伤心
And it saddens me
是因为我呕心沥血
because I bled and toiled
背负骂名
and allowed myself to be hated,
都是为了保护你
all for your protection,
好让你觉得自己独一无二
all so that you could believe that you were truly special.
但换来的不是感激  而是冷嘲热讽
But instead of gratitude, I get scorn, ridicule, mockery.
最糟的是
And -- worst of all --
还有一个不放过任何机会
a daughter who sends in her clan of good, old boys to kill me,
使遍浑身解数
your own blood,
想杀了自己的女儿
every chance you get!
你的人生才是可悲的
It is your life that is sad.
你才是不正常的
It is you who cannot be normal.
你才是那个不懂爱的
It is you who have no comprehension of love.
所以呢
So, what?
你每次看到我都恶心吗
Your stomach turns every time you look at me?
我来说破吧  奥利维亚
Well, let me be the one to break it to you, Olivia --
你看到的不过是自己罢了
you are simply looking in the mirror.
你...
You...
奥利维亚
Olivia...
当心点
watch yourself.
你是开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
是在...开玩笑吗
Are you... kidding me?
你...
You j--
你居然对自己父亲开枪
You -- you just shot your own father.
居然对我开枪
Y-you just shot me.
我真的
Never,
真的从没想过
never in a million years
你会有胆量
did I think that you would be willing...
扣下板机
to pull the trigger.
你第一次上幼儿园的前一晚
It was the night before your first day of kindergarten.
你...
You were
你紧张到睡不着
you were so anxious that you couldn't sleep.
我把留声机拿去你房间
I brought the record player into your room...
放了这张唱片
and put on that album.
史提夫·旺达的歌声响起
Stevie Wonder sang.
只有十分钟  你就睡着了
And you were out... in 10 minutes.
不管你多不愿承认
No matter how hard you try to deny it...
我死了
you will miss me...
你会想我的
when I'm gone.
天呐
Oh god.
可恶
Oh, crap.
我的牙
Oh, my tooth.
新补的吗
The new one?
是的
Yeah.
没人想杀你
No one's gonna kill ya,
我是该杀你  但我不会的
I was supposed to, but I -- I wouldn't have.
我不相信
I don't believe you.
我下不了手  罗宾
I can't kill you, Robin.
你打了我
You hurt me.
是你先打我的
You hurt me first.
奶奶死了
Granny died.
弗兰奶奶吗
Granny Fran?
不是吧  什么时候
Oh, no. When?
几周前
A few weeks ago.
-你知道她病了  -是的
- You knew she was sick. - Yeah.
知道  只是  我没...
Yeah, I just -- I-I didn't --
最后病情恶化
It was bad at the end.
我陪她走的  帮了她一把
I helped her along, made it quick.
-不想让她受罪  -当然
- Didn't want her to suffer. - Of course.
对不起
Look, I'm sorry.
我该多打电话给你的
I should call you more.
我知道你没有...
I know you don't have...
我该多打给你的
I should call you more.
但你毁了一切  查理
But you ruined everything, Charlie.
-好吧  -没错  你毁掉了哈克的整个人生
- Okay. - No, you ruined Huck's whole life.
好吧  好吧
Okay. Okay.
我想或许我可以弥补
I guess maybe I could un-ruin it.
怎样
How?
我有一些B613的资料  我们的所做作为
I have these files on B613, all the stuff we did.
我收到指令将这些文件从储物柜里偷出来
I got orders to steal them from this storage locker,
然后用空白文件替换
replace them with blanks.
我本应该把所有的文件都送还指挥官
I was supposed to give them all back to Command,
但我私自留一些  你懂的  以防万一
but I kept a few for myself, you know, as insurance.
你认为这能帮上忙吗
You think it'd help?
谢谢
Thanks.
嘿  宝贝
Hey, baby.
我需要一些情报
I need some information.
我需要知道他可能去的地方
I need to know where he could have gone.
我怎么会知道
How should I know?
你知道一些内幕
You know something.
他将你活生生地囚禁起来
He kept you in a hole, alive.
而且他还来探望你吗
And he -- what, he visited you?
一周一次吗
Once a week?
-每天  -每天都来
- Every day. - Every day.
他每天都来探望你
He visited you every day.
他对你有种变态扭曲的痴迷
He's got some sick, twisted obsession with you.
他把你囚禁起来
He keeps you locked away,
每天放你出来一次欣赏他囚笼里的宠物
pulls you out once a day to admire his pet in a cage.
你肯定知道一些内幕
You have to know something.
你耗费数年的时间监视他
You spent years watching him.
你对他的疯狂行径了如指掌
You have a PHD in his crazy.
你肯定知道他现在的位置
You have to have some idea where he is,
他可能去的地方
where he could have gone.
我现在就要答案
I want some answers now!
女儿  你必须向前看
Girl, you need to move on.
你们父女两总只是互相指责
All you two do is talk about each other.
你和他一模一样
You're just like him.
我一点也不像他
I'm nothing like him.
真的吗
Really?
在我看来
Way I see it,
你很享受为总统效力
you're serving at the pleasure of a president,
又和B613的人纠缠不清
running around with boys from B613.
你四周看看
And look around, boo.
我身陷囹圄  你来探望我
I'm in a cage. You're visiting me.
你打算每天都来还是...
You planning to come every day or...?
他毁了你
He ruined you.
泪流成河吧  丽芙  随你便
Cry me a river, Livvie. Whatever.
我得走了
I have to go.
再见  妈妈
Goodbye, mom.
明天见
I'll see you tomorrow.
听说你辞职了
I heard you resigned.
行李还真不少
Not exactly packing light.
那个  没错  那是詹姆斯的地方
Oh, that. No. That was James' side.
我不忍心用
I couldn't bear to use it.
去哪儿
So, where to?
想去欧洲
I'm thinking Europe.
欧洲人能够接纳失败与名声扫地的人
They have a long history of accepting failure and disgrace.
西恩娜·罗杰斯今早说我是一个"典型同性恋"
Sienna Rogers called me "A gay stereotype" this morning.
我辛苦工作  三十年来
I worked so hard, 30 years of --
我一直奋斗不息才进入了当今权力最大的办公室
I clawed my way into the most powerful house in the world,
现在一切都没了
and it's all gone.
我对着镜子
I look in the mirror,
我已认不清自己的面目
and I don't even know who I am anymore.
一个典型的同性恋
Eh, a gay stereotype.
塞勒斯
Cyrus.
什么事
Hmm. Yes?
我要你仔细给我听好
I need you to listen to me very carefully
因为我现在要用我所认识的塞勒斯
because I'm going to speak to you right now
跟人说话的方式来跟你说话
the way the Cyrus Beene I know would speak to you.
我不...
I don't --
你是什么时候决定允许他们打垮你的
When did you decide to let them ruin you?
你说什么
Excuse me?
你的生活不公平  那又怎样
So your life's unfair. So what?
生活本来就是这样
That's how it is.
他们在媒体上戏谑你
So, they're mean-girling you in the press,
嘲笑你
they're calling you names
难道就伤害了你内心深处脆弱的一面吗
that hurt your little soft spots deep inside?
那又怎样
Well, so what?
事情本就如此
That's how it is.
你失去了你深爱的人
So you lost someone you loved.
你失去了一个能让你感受家庭温暖的人
You lost the one person who felt like family.
好吧  猜猜怎么着
Well, guess what.
成熟一点  因为这就是人生
Grow the hell up because that is how it is!
我认识的塞勒斯·比尼
The Cyrus Beene I know
不会躲在自己半空的衣橱里
doesn't hide in his half-empty closet
像一个臭婊子吓得尿裤子
and wet his pants like a little bitch baby.
我认识的塞勒斯是一个爱国者
The Cyrus I know is a patriot.
他咬紧牙关
He bites the bullet,
不惜一切代价为国家效力
and he does what it takes to serve the republic at all costs.
我想知道  此时此刻  你到底是谁
So, I want to know, right now, in this moment, who you are.
因为我此刻
Because the pathetic shell of a person
所看到这个可悲的身影并不配
I'm looking at right now doesn't deserve to stand
站在总统办公室里的总统徽章上面
on the presidential seal in the oval office,
更别说为总统出谋划策
let alone tell the president what to do.
-你是谁  塞  -丽芙
- Who are you, Cy? - Liv.
- Who are you, Cy?! - Liv!
你是谁  塞
Who are you, Cy?
我是这个世上最有权力的人之一
I am one of the most powerful men in the world.
你是谁
Who are you!?
我是这个世上最有权力的人之一
I am one of the most powerful men in the world.
是吗  所以你不是什么臭婊子吗
Oh, yeah? So, you're not a bitch baby?
我管理着这个国家
I run this country.
-我不是任何人的婊子  -我可不知道
- I'm nobody's bitch baby. - I don't know.
在我看来你还是有点像
You still sound like a little bitch baby to me.
我不是个婊子
I am not a little bitch baby!
那就做出点样子给我看
Then show me!
现在就证明给我看
Prove it to me right now!
让我看看你是谁  塞勒斯·比尼
Show me who you are, Cyrus Beene!
婚礼什么时候举行
When's the wedding?
-还没决定  -夏天
- We haven't decided. - Summer.
好吧  也许是在夏天
Okay. Well, summer, maybe.
我得问一个观众想知道的问题
I have to ask the question I know my audience is asking.
你们现在已经订婚了
Engaged? Now?
有些人可能认为那是为了方便
Some might see that as fairly convenient.
我之前很害怕  现在也是
I was scared. I am scared.
这让我提心吊胆
This is very scary.
但这些照片的流出让我明白
But the pictures coming out made it clear.
我再也瞒不下去了  我也意识到自己不想瞒下去
I couldn't hide anymore, and I realized I didn't want to.
我可以为自己违法行为道歉
I can apologize for breaking the law.
我可以为让总统蒙羞道歉
I can apologize for disgracing the president.
但我不能因为自己
But I just can't bring myself
坠入情网而道歉
to apologize for falling in love.
-他们是灵魂伴侣  -他们是罪犯
- They're soulmates. - They're criminals!
拜托  塞勒斯·比尼都道歉过了
Oh, come on! Cyrus Beene apologized.
所以突然就要免除他的罪责了吗
And that's supposed to magically absolve him of his crimes?
那可是卖淫罪
I mean, prostitution?
对传统家庭价值观来说那样真的好吗
How's that for good, old family values?
别因为你自己严格的道德观就对我不满  布鲁克
Oh, don't get all puritanical on me, Brooke.
这就像《风月俏佳人》一样  多浪漫啊
It's "Pretty woman." It's romantic.
而且早前的民调数据显示
And if these early poll numbers are any indication,
美国人民都同意了
America agrees.
我看了你的采访
Saw your interview.
很感人
It was very moving.
我娶了个男妓
Hey. I'm marrying a whore.
至少我知道钱都花在哪儿了  对吧
At least I know what I'm paying for, right?
我会给你倒一杯威士忌
I'll pour you a scotch
如果你能告诉我如何处理西安哥拉问题
if you'll tell me what I should do about West Angola.
杯子在那个箱子里
Glasses are in the other box.
即使共和党内压力重重
Despite increasing pressure from his fellow republicans,
格兰特总统
发生爆炸案并不意味着需要战争来解决
总统坚持
the president has held firm
拒绝向西安哥拉派遣兵力
in his refusal to send troops into West Angola.
来自白宫内部的消息强调称
Sources inside the White House are emphatic
不会有战争
there will be no war.
我在街上听到
I'm hearing word on the street
你丈夫压根儿就没准备打仗
that your husband isn't going to war after all.
听起来是那么一回事儿
Doesn't sound like it, does it?
你知道那意味着什么吗
Do you understand what that means?
菲茨在党内已经尽失人心
Fitz has lost the party.
是总统先生  莉兹  "菲茨"不是你能叫的
It's Mr. President, Liz. Not "Fitz."
抱歉  我有得罪过你吗
I'm sorry. Did I do something to offend you?
我以为咱俩已经达成了共识
I thought you and I were on the same page.
因为我们都跟安德鲁有一腿吗
Because wee both screwing Andrew?
那并不能使我们成为朋友
That doesn't make us friends.
只会增加我们患上同一种性病的风险
It just makes us both at risk for the same STDs.
我不怪你
I don't blame you.
我和在我之后的女人都知道
I know as well as the next gal
安德鲁在床上是多么开放
how generous Andrew is in bed.
他很有奉献精神  但他很弱
He is...dedicated. But he's weak.
绝不会是总统之位的有力竞争者
Certainly not a presidential contender.
所以下一次大选开始时
So, when the next election rolls around,
我希望你能赌对人
I'd make damn sure you bet the right horse,
因为就上床而言
because when it comes to screwing someone,
我远不及安德鲁那样温和
I'm not nearly as gentle as Andrew.
我会让你痛不欲生
From me, it will hurt.
你可以进去的  波普女士
You're free to go in, Ms. Pope.
没事  夏洛特
It's okay, Charlotte.
下次吧
Another time.
求你听听我的心声
Just hear me out.
等你被警察抓了我会听的
I will hear you out when you are in the back of a police car.
-我要报警了  -拜托
- I'm calling 911. - Please?
我需要你知道为什么我会变成这样
I need you to know why I'm like this.
我需要你看看这些
I need you to read these.
看看就好
Just read them.
这会是我请求你做的最后一件事
It's the last thing I'll ever ask you to do.
奎恩  你的脸
Quinn. Your face.
我没事
Oh, I'm fine.
我已经搞明白了  韦科
I figured it out. Waco.
不是城市名  这是个首字母缩略词
It's not the city. It's an acronym.
WACO
W-A-C-O.
西安哥拉商业组织
West Angola Commercial Organization.
这是个西安哥拉政府的附属机构
It's a subsidiary of the West Angolan government.
杰里米·温斯洛的律所帮他们管理在美国的资产
Jeremy Winslow's law firm manages their American assets.
总统先生  谢谢你能见我
Mr. President. Thanks for seeing me.
我能坐下吗
May I?
西安哥拉
West Angola?
是那个炸副总统的国家吗
Isn't that the country that bombed the vice president?
而他  你可能记得
Who, as you may recall,
他是我们一个同盟
is one of our friendly neighborhood conspirators.
你觉得那是巧合吗
Do you think that's a coincidence?
我觉得不是
In fact, I know it's not.
西安哥拉的事
This West Angola thing.
我也希望自己大吃一惊
I wish I could say I was surprised.
对大多数政府来说
Most administrations,
如果有人想杀副总统  他们会还以颜色
someone tries to kill the vice president, you hit them back.
但是你不属于大多数中的一员对吧
But you're not most administrations, are you?
看到了吗
You see that?
他往柱子后面站的时候特意确认了位置
He's checked his position in relation to that column.
你看他  他换了位置
Now look what he does. He changed positions.
就好像他知道在那里才安全
Like he knew he'd be safe there.
他知道会有爆炸发生
He knew the explosion was coming.
看着我被炸飞
Watching me get my ass blown off
对你而言应该够了
should have been enough for you.
不幸的是  你甚至根本不在乎我
Unfortunately, you don't respect me enough to care.
我或许也知道这点
And maybe I knew that.
或许我早就知道你会作何反应
Maybe I knew you'd react that way.
如果他们想这样开战
If this is about them getting the war they wanted,
-那为什么要拍丽芙的照片  -不知道
- why take pictures of Liv? - I don't know.
整个谜团中只有这一点还说不通了
It's the one piece of the puzzle that doesn't make sense.
来得正是时候
You're just in time.
你好像很开心
You look happy.
要进来吗
You're coming in?
我在亚当斯摩根一个非常小的红酒店里
I found two bottles of Du Bellay
发现了杜贝莱酒  竟然有两瓶
at this tiny, little wine shop in Adams Morgan. Two.
丽芙  我需要跟你谈谈你父亲的事
Liv, I need to talk to you about your father.
我不想谈我父亲
I don't want to talk about my father.
我还给你买了啤酒...
I also got you beer --
这是进口的  卖的人说你肯定会喜欢
Something imported the guy said would amaze you.
但鉴于是啤酒  所以...
But it's beer, so...
丽芙  我抓到他了
Liv, I had him.
我抓到你父亲了  然后又让他跑了
I had your father, and I lost him.
好了  烤箱里在加热你爱吃的汉堡
Okay. There's gettysburger warming in the oven.
我还去那家用第一夫人名字
I also went to that pizza place
给派命名的披萨店
that names the pies after First Ladies.
我买了个朵莉·麦迪逊[第四届总统夫人]
I got us a Dolly Madison,
所以你就松开裤腰带敞开肚皮吃吧
so unzip your pants now because we are eating.
-丽芙  -我不想谈我父亲的事
- Liv. - I don't want to talk about my father.
我再也不想谈论他了
I'm done talking about my father.
我对这些唱片简直着迷
I'm obsessed with all these albums.
这个专辑  简直太棒了
This collection, it's amazing.
-我差点就抓到他了  -别说了
- I almost had him. - Let it go.
这张  这张是我最喜欢的之一
This one. This is one of my favorites.
丽芙
Liv.
-跟我一起跳舞  -但是...
- Dance with me. - But --
他已经走了  我们不关心
He's gone. We don't care.
放手吧
Let it go.
丽芙
Liv!
闭嘴跳舞吧
Shut up and dance.
天哪  我好爱你
Man, do I love you.
我想要佛蒙特的菲茨
I want Vermont with Fitz.
好吧
Oh. Okay.
我也想要阳光下的你
I also want the sun with you.
所以...
So...
我不是在做出选择
I'm not choosing.
我不是选择杰克  也不是选择菲茨
I'm not choosing Jake. I'm not choosing Fitz.
我选自己
I choose me.
我选择奥利维亚
I'm choosing Olivia.
现在  奥利维亚正在跳舞
And right now, Olivia is dancing.
我在跳舞  杰克  我好自由
I'm dancing, Jake. I'm free.
所以你要么跟我一起跳舞
Now, you can dance with me
要么离开我的舞池
or you can get off my dance floor.
我自己一个人跳没关系
I'm fine dancing alone.
我从没在钢琴上跟人做过爱
I've never had sex on top of the piano.
会冷吗
Cold?
会很滑吧
Mm, slippery.
我去拿条毯子
I'll get a blanket.
你不要动哦
Don't move.
我还能去哪里
Where would I go?
要不我再拿个枕头吧  当垫子用
Maybe I'll grab a pillow. For cushion.
我觉得我们是不是该在钢琴边上做啊
I'm thinking maybe we should do it against the piano.
万一我们俩都爬到钢琴上
Because if we both climb on that thing
把那玩意儿压垮了怎么办...
and it comes crashing down...
第一  声音会很大
Well, one -- very loud.
第二  会很疼  而且不好向救护人员解释
And two -- painful and hard to explain to the paramedics.
但是我还是愿意试试
But, hey, I'm willing to go for it,
不过我们俩都精力旺盛
but we are very athletic,
我跟你说  我们绝对能搞坏一架钢琴的
I'm telling you -- we could break a piano.
或者说我是不是太自信了
Or am I being an optimist?
丽芙
Liv?
告诉我  总统先生
Tell me, Mr. President.
这个世界上有什么
What's the one thing in the world
你离开就活不了了
you can't live without?
有什么  如果我们夺走
The one thing that, if it were taken away from you,
你会不惜一切夺回来
you would do everything in your power to get back?
你对她做了什么
What did you do to her?
你做了什么
What did you do?
你现在觉得这场战争如何  总统先生
How you likin' that war now, sir?
丽芙
Liv?